{"tossups": [{"question": "A man decides to first call his wife and then his girlfriend at the end of a story by this author in which the protagonist meets a chimney sweep named J.P. who describes meeting his wife Roxy. In another story by this author, two characters argue about whether \u201cvessel\u201d or \u201cvassal\u201d is the right word after a cardiologist comments that he would be a knight if he could come back in a different life. The protagonist of another of this author\u2019s stories closes his eyes while (*) drawing the title structure in an attempt to describe it to a blind man named Robert. This author of \u201cWhere I\u2019m Calling From\u201d also wrote a story in which Mel, Terri, Nick, and Laura sit at a table discussing the title emotion. For 10 points, name this author of \u201cCathedral\u201d and \u201cWhat We Talk About When We Talk About Love.\u201d", "answer": "Raymond Carver", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Raymond <b><u>Carver</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Raymond Carver", "Carver"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One section of this novel sees the protagonist live in a society ruled by women, while another section sees Rajah killed by his half-brother Dasa. Those sections follow a chapter called \u201cThe Legend.\u201d In this novel, the protagonist drowns when challenged to a swimming race in a mountain lake by Tito and earlier befriends Father Jacobus while at a monastery in (*) Mariafels. This novel\u2019s protagonist begins teaching Plinio Designori\u2019s son after resigning from his rank as master. This novel begins in Castalia where the protagonist is recruited by the Music Master and later becomes Magister Ludi. For 10 points, name this novel by Hermann Hesse about Joseph Knecht, a master of the titular game.", "answer": "The Glass Bead Game [or Das Glasperlenspiel; accept Magister Ludi until read]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Glass Bead Game</u></b> [or <b><u>Das Glasperlenspiel</u></b>; accept <b><u>Magister Ludi</u></b> until read]", "acceptable": ["The Glass Bead Game", "Glass Bead Game", "Das Glasperlenspiel", "Magister Ludi"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poem most famous for this phrase begins by saying the youth must learn \u201cTo suffer hardness with good cheer\u201d in order to \u201cMake him one day the Parthian's dread.\u201d This phrase in that poem is followed by the claim that \u201cDeath's darts e'en flying feet o'ertake.\u201d This phrase titles another poem that describes \u201cHis hanging face, like a devil\u2019s sick of sin.\u201d That poem wishes its audience could hear (*) \u201cthe blood / Come gargling from the froth-corrupted lungs,\u201d and describes \u201cAn ecstasy of fumbling\u201d before \u201cfitting the clumsy helmets in time.\u201d This phrase ends that poem, which urges the listener not to tell this phrase \u201cTo children ardent for some desperate glory\u201d and describes it as \u201cthe old Lie.\u201d For 10 points, give this supposedly-patriotic Latin phrase first used by Horace which also titles a World War I poem by Wilfred Owen.", "answer": "\u201cDulce et decorum est pro patria mori\u201d [accept \u201cIt is sweet and proper to die for one\u2019s country\u201d or similar translations]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cDulce et decorum est pro patria mori\u201d</u></b> [accept <b><u>It is sweet</u></b> or <b><u>proper to die for one\u2019s country</u></b> or <b><u>similar translations</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["\u201cDulce et decorum est pro patria mori\u201d", "\u201cDulce et decorum est pro patria mori\u201d", "It is sweet", "proper to die for one\u2019s country", "similar translations"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of this story is able to return home because another person found an \u201cobscure reference in Maimonides that favors you.\u201d The protagonist of this story is convinced by another character that \u201cthere is no God\u201d and that there is only a \u201cthick mire.\u201d Another character in this story tells the protagonist to check on the goat before ushering the apprentice out of her house. The (*) rabbi tells the protagonist of this story that his neighbors who shame him will not go to heaven, before his daughter tricks him. The protagonist of this story leaves the town of Frampol after his wife Elka tells him that none of her children are his. The protagonist of this story is convinced by the Spirit of Evil to urinate in dough. For 10 points, name this short story by Isaac Bashevis Singer about the title gullible baker.", "answer": "\u201cGimpel the Fool\u201d [or \"Gimpel tam\"]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cGimpel the Fool\u201d</u></b> [or <b><u>Gimpel tam</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["\u201cGimpel the Fool\u201d", "\u201cGimpel the Fool\u201d", "Gimpel tam"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "It\u2019s not Oscar Wilde, but in a play by this author, Ruth gives cucumber sandwiches to another character to restore her energy. Two characters in a play by this author try to prevent arguing by creating two minutes of silence through the code words \u201cSolomon Isaacs.\u201d In that play by this author, ex-spouses (*) Elyot and Amanda run away together after finding out they share a terrace during their respective honeymoons. Another play by this author of Private Lives sees Madame Arcati accidentally summon Elvira during a s\u00e9ance, who haunts her husband Charles Condomine. This playwright was inspired by Percy Shelley\u2019s \u201cTo A Skylark\u201d to title one of his plays. For 10 points, name this English playwright of Blithe Spirit.", "answer": "Noel Coward", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Noel <b><u>Coward</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Noel Coward", "Coward"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this novel dates the Gangster and is driven home by \u201ca man with no face\u201d when he abandons her. That character\u2019s daughter later burns her wig on a stove. The protagonist of this novel falls for a character who later ditches him for the older Manny, causing him to attempt suicide by drinking rum. The protagonist\u2019s mother is almost beaten to death in a sugar-cane field but is saved by a \u201cgolden-eyed mongoose.\u201d The doctor Abelard is imprisoned after refusing to allow the \u201cfailed cattle thief\u201d to rape his his daughter Jacquelyn, causing a (*) \u201cfuku\u201d curse to haunt the central family of this novel. The narrator of this novel receives a quartet of science fiction novels mailed by the protagonist after his death at the hands of \u201cThe Captain.\u201d Yunior narrates, for 10 points, what novel about the title nerdy, overweight Dominican, written by Junot Diaz?", "answer": "The Brief Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Brief Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Brief Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao", "Brief Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poem about this person says that \u201cevery killing for him is delight.\u201d The narrator of one poem primarily targeted at this person claims that she has \u201cpleaded / For [her son] to come home,\u201d even going as far as to fling herself \u201cat the hangman\u2019s feet.\u201d In one poem about this person, he has \u201cthick fingers\u201d that are \u201cbulky and fat like live-baits.\u201d That poem about this person calls him the (*) \u201cKremlin Highlander\u201d and is an epigram written by Osip Mandelstam. In an Arthur Koestler novel, Rubashov is arrested on the orders of a fictionalized version of this person. Anna Akhmatova mourned the arrest of her son Lev Gumilov by the NKVD under this person\u2019s regime in Requiem. \u201cNo. 1\u201d in Darkness at Noon represents, for 10 points, what Soviet dictator?", "answer": "Joseph Stalin [or Joseph Vissarionovich Stalin; or Ioseb Besarionis dze Jughashvili]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Joseph <b><u>Stalin</u></b> [or <b><u>Joseph Vissarionovich Stalin</u></b>; or <b><u>Ioseb Besarionis dze Jughashvili</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Joseph Stalin", "Stalin", "Joseph Vissarionovich Stalin", "Ioseb Besarionis dze Jughashvili"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one play by this author, Alexandra tells the protagonist that she will not idly watch her be the one \u201cwho eats the earth.\u201d Dr. Joe Cardin stops a character\u2019s plan to get out of class by claiming she had \u201cheart pains\u201d in one play by this author. One character in that play by this author recites The Merchant of Venice\u2019s \u201cquality of mercy\u201d speech. Leo steals a safe deposit box that contains (*) Union Pacific bonds worth 88,000 dollars in a play by this author. In another play by this author, Mary Tilford accuses her teachers Karen Wright and Martha Dobie of having a lesbian affair, resulting in Dobie\u2019s suicide. The wheelchair-bound Horace dies of a heart attack after his wife Regina Hubbard withholds medication from him in another play by this author. For 10 points, name this American playwright of The Children\u2019s Hour and The Little Foxes.", "answer": "Lillian Hellman", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Lillian <b><u>Hellman</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Lillian Hellman", "Hellman"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a novel by this author, the drug addict Nathan Bogle prevents Natalie, who changed her name from Keisha, from jumping off a bridge. Another novel by this author opens with a man flipping a coin and deciding against gassing himself in his car, even though the coin flip said otherwise. Marcus Chalfen runs the FutureMouse project in that novel, which is opposed by Joshua, who is part of the radical animal-rights group FATE. Millat, who joins a Muslim brotherhood, is the son of (*) Samad in one novel by this author. This author wrote about Leah Hanwell and Felix Cooper, two residents of the title London postcode area, in NW, while Archie Jones marries the former Jehovah\u2019s Witness Clara Bowden in another novel by this author. For 10 points, name this British author of White Teeth.", "answer": "Zadie Adeline Smith", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Zadie Adeline <b><u>Smith</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Zadie Adeline Smith", "Smith"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The penultimate poem of this collection revolves around a particular secret which \u201cgushes out from\u201d the speaker\u2019s heart \u201cwho still sits smiling.\u201d One of its poems is set in locations including \u201cwhere the world has not been broken up into fragments by narrow domestic walls.\u201d The final poem in this collection depicts the \u201crain cloud of July\u201d hanging low before imagining many homesick cranes. Children meet on the endless seashore and do not know how to (*) \u201ccast nets\u201d in this collection, which contains a poem concluding to \u201cLet my country awake!\u201d William Butler Yeats wrote an introduction to this collection, whose first poem declares \u201cThou hast made me endless, such is thy pleasure.\u201d For 10 points, name these \u201cSong Offerings\u201d by Rabindranath Tagore.", "answer": "Gitanjali [accept Song Of erings before read]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Gitanjali</u></b> [accept <b><u>Song Of erings</u></b> before read]", "acceptable": ["Gitanjali", "Gitanjali", "Song Of erings"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this novel says, \u201cI want to see you live it. It is more than a notion\u201d to another character after a prayer. A man in this novel commits suicide after being arrested along with a group of robbers in a subway station. That man, Richard, was the boyfriend of Elizabeth, who used to work as a cleaning woman with Florence. Another character in this novel had two sons named Royal, one of whom died in Chicago. The protagonist of this novel climbs a hill in Central Park in the section \u201cThe Seventh Day,\u201d and he later finds out that his brother (*) Roy was stabbed in a knife fight. The protagonist of this novel goes to a movie on his fourteenth birthday and attends his stepfather Gabriel\u2019s church, the Temple of the Fire Baptized. John Grimes is the protagonist of, for 10 points, what semi-autobiographical novel by James Baldwin?", "answer": "Go Tell It on the Mountain", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Go Tell It on the Mountain</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Go Tell It on the Mountain", "Go Tell It on the Mountain"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "He\u2019s not from The Tempest, but this character asks if he is in Africa after seeing another character\u2019s mask and tells that character he has fallen from the Moon. This character supposedly writes a comedy scene that is stolen by Moliere and makes the latter a success. This character crosses enemy lines twice a day to deliver letters, causing the letters\u2019 recipient to bring a feast for the soldiers. This character is introduced at the Hotel Burgundy, where he throws a bag of coins to pay for admissions to a play at which he angrily throws the actor Montfleury off stage. This character, who boasts of his (*) \u201cpanache,\u201d dies in a convent when a log drops on him moments after he reveals that he wrote all of Christian\u2019s letters to Roxanne. For 10 points, name this title swordsman of an Edmond Rostand play known for his large nose.", "answer": "Cyrano de Bergerac [prompt on de Bergerac]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Cyrano de Bergerac</u></b> [prompt on <u>de Bergerac</u>]", "acceptable": ["Cyrano de Bergerac", "Cyrano de Bergerac"], "promptable": ["de Bergerac"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Description Acceptable. A poem asks a woman made \u201cOut of maize & air\u201d if she is \u201cmoved\u2026 not, restless, waiting for\u201d this man. A poem titled for this man claims that the heavens ought to reward him \u201cmanifold\u201d after mentioning love that \u201crivers cannot quench.\u201d One poem says that this man will \u201clisten while you read a song\u201d and ends with a mention of a \u201clost candle like the firefly loves.\u201d One poem compares this man\u2019s love to (*) \u201call the riches the East doth hold\u201d and prizes it \u201cmore than whole mines of gold.\u201d This man\u2019s wife is the subject of a John Berryman homage, and a poem titled for him begins \u201cif ever two were one, then surely we.\u201d For 10 points, name or describe this \u201cdear and loving\u201d partner of the poet who penned The Tenth Muse Lately Sprung Up In America.", "answer": "Anne Bradstreet\u2019s husband [accept Simon Bradstreet; prompt on Bradstreet until \u201chusband\u201d is said, then accept after; do not accept or prompt on Anne Bradstreet]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Anne Bradstreet\u2019s husband</u></b> [accept <b><u>Simon Bradstreet</u></b>; prompt on <u>Bradstreet</u> until \u201chusband\u201d is said, then accept after; do not accept or prompt on \"Anne Bradstreet\"]", "acceptable": ["Anne Bradstreet\u2019s husband", "Anne Bradstreet\u2019s husband", "Simon Bradstreet"], "promptable": ["Bradstreet"], "rejectable": ["Anne Bradstreet"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The speaker of one poem by this author says \u201cbad luck was my god\u201d after calling \u201cfor plagues to choke me with sand.\" A figure in that poem yells \u201cYou\u2019ll always be a hyena.\" Another poem by this man was inspired by Jules Verne\u2019s The Adventures of Captain Hatteras. That poem declares \u201cthe bitter redness of love ferments.\u201d A prose poem by this author contains sections such as \u201cThe Impossible\u201d and \u201cBad Blood\u201d and begins by recalling when its speaker\u2019s life was \u201cone long party.\" The speaker of another poem by this man says \u201cI was indifferent to all (*) crews\u201d after describing an assault of \u201cyelping redskins.\" That speaker claims \u201cI no longer felt myself guided by haulers\u201d while \u201cgoing down impassive Rivers.\" For 10 points, name this French poet who included two Deliriums in his A Season in Hell and wrote \u201cThe Drunken Boat.\"", "answer": "Jean Nicolas Arthur Rimbaud", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Jean Nicolas Arthur <b><u>Rimbaud</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Jean Nicolas Arthur Rimbaud", "Rimbaud"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Witnesses disagree on whether this character limps on his left or right leg, though he actually has no limp at all. This character carries a wooden cane with a knob shaped like a poodle's head, and is often called a foreigner. This man calls Matthew Levi a fool, asking if Levi wants to \u201cskin the whole earth,\u201d and likens the existence of good and evil to light and shadows. A pince-nez wearing follower of this character shoots a pistol that rains (*) money on a crowd, immediately inciting chaos. This man predicts that an atheist will be decapitated by a tram, and he later uses that atheist\u2019s head as a cup during a ball. This man says to a title character, \"Now you can finish your novel with one phrase!\" after encouraging him to set Pontius Pilate free. For 10 points, what professor of black magic declares, \"Manuscripts don't burn,\" in Mikhail Bulgakov's The Master and Margarita?", "answer": "Professor Woland [accept Satan, the Devil, or equivalents]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Professor <b><u>Woland</u></b> [accept <b><u>Satan, the Devil,</u></b> or equivalents]", "acceptable": ["Professor Woland", "Woland", "Satan, the Devil,"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The title object of one poem by this author \u201cdrove in the dark to leeward / She struck\u2014not a reef or a rock.\u201d That poem by this author opens with an invocation to \u201cGod! giver of breath and bread.\u201d In another poem by this author, the narrator asks, \u201cwho knows how?\u201d when describing \u201cwhatever is fickle, freckled.\u201d That narrator implores people to \u201cpraise him\u201d who \u201cfathers-forth whose beauty is past change.\u201d Another poem by this author is dedicated to the (*) \u201chappy memory of five Franciscan Nuns\u201d that drowned on the title ship while escaping from Germany. This poet opened one of his works by stating \u201cglory be to God for dappled things.\u201d For 10 points, name this English poet who pioneered \u201csprung rhythm\u201d and wrote poems such as \u201cThe Wreck of the Deutschland\u201d and \u201cPied Beauty.\u201d", "answer": "Gerard Manley Hopkins", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Gerard Manley <b><u>Hopkins</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Gerard Manley Hopkins", "Hopkins"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A novel written by an author from this country is dedicated to the \u201cworm who first gnawed on the cold flesh of my corpse.\u201d The title character of another novel from this country accuses his wife Capitu of cheating on him. In another novel from this country, Ramiro Bastos feuds over the modernization of its town of Ilheus with Mundinho (*) Falcao. Bento Santiago is nicknamed \u201cLord Taciturn\u201d in one novel from this country, which is titled Dom Casmurro. An author from this country wrote a novel in which the bar owner Nacib Saad has an affair with the protagonist, titled Gabriela, Clove and Cinnamon. For 10 points, name this South American country of Joachim Machado de Assis and Jorge Amado, who wrote in Portuguese.", "answer": "Federative Republic of Brazil [or Rep\u00fablica Federativa do Brasil]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Federative Republic of <b><u>Brazil</u></b> [or <b><u>Rep\u00fablica Federativa do Brasil</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Federative Republic of Brazil", "Brazil", "Rep\u00fablica Federativa do Brasil"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An essay criticizing this work compares an exclamation made by one character to \u201cthose improving mottoes sometimes found hanging on the walls of furnished rooms.\u201d In a collection named after this novel, Silas finds a broken record player and is eventually trapped inside a burning house, while in a different section Johnny Boy is brutally shot before the protagonist wraps a gun with a white sheet. Shortly after the publication of this book, its author detailed the sources and inspiration for its characters in this work\u2019s namesake (*) \u201cKey.\u201d This novel\u2019s characters inspired namesake \u201citude\u201d memorabilia, and stage shows titled for it borrowed heavily from the minstrel tradition. James Baldwin\u2019s \u201cEverybody\u2019s Protest Novel\u201d criticizes, for 10 points, what abolitionist work by Harriet Beecher Stowe?", "answer": "Uncle Tom\u2019s Cabin", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Uncle Tom\u2019s Cabin</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Uncle Tom\u2019s Cabin", "Uncle Tom\u2019s Cabin"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character created by this author refuses to play more than two songs during a music recording session and obsessively talks about funeral urns in a story dedicated to Charlie Parker. The protagonist of another novel by this author talks about passages and pits with Talita, and earlier spends hours trying to straighten nails in the floor. That protagonist later tries to make a bridge between two buildings. In that novel by this author, the protagonist joins a group of Bohemian intellectuals called the (*) Serpent Club. This author of \u201cThe Pursuer'' wrote about Etienne, who goes with the protagonist to the old man Morelli\u2019s flat in this author\u2019s best-known novel, which can be read in multiple orders and contains \u201cexpendable chapters.\u201d For 10 points, name this Argentine author who wrote about Horacio Oliveira in Hopscotch.", "answer": "Julio Florencio Cortazar", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Julio Florencio <b><u>Cortazar</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Julio Florencio Cortazar", "Cortazar"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this novel remarks, \u201cThat\u2019s the best of all. Four aces and the joker\u201d after shooting a revolver at the title character five times. Another person in this novel shouts, \u201cCover his face!\u201d and is given a sheet from the Jolly Cricketers. A man in this novel is chased to the town of Port Burdock after betraying the title character. That man is Thomas Marvel. The title character describes his plan for a \u201cReign of Terror\u201d to Doctor Kemp in this novel, which begins after he arrives at the (*) Bramblehurst station. Part of this novel takes place at the Coach and Horses hotel, which is run by the Halls in Iping. This novel\u2019s title character, the scientist Griffin, steals food and clothes in order to conceal his title attribute. For 10 points, name this H. G. Wells novel about a man who cannot be seen.", "answer": "The Invisible Man [DO NOT accept or prompt on \u201cInvisible Man\u201d]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Invisible Man</u></b> [DO NOT accept or prompt on \u201cInvisible Man\u201d]", "acceptable": ["The Invisible Man", "Invisible Man"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}